<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ivan Fesiuk - #Full Stack Developer | Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://eneus.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ivan Fesiuk - #Full Stack Developer | Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://eneus.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating Systems for ASUS Tinker Board</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/blog/os-for-asus-tinker-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/blog/os-for-asus-tinker-board/</guid>
      <description>Hi dear reader. In previews article I had post How to connect DSI and CSI cable to tinker board with a some Frequently Asked Question. In this Article I had collected all available OS for single-board computer ASUS Tinker Board. Based on this computer i will to construct my robot with AI implementation and computer vision. Actually this the first reason why i had select Tinker Board that based on Rockchip RK3288 processor with 4x Cores &amp;ldquo;Cortex-A17&amp;rdquo; with frequency 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drone Communicator Interface</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/projects/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/projects/8/</guid>
      <description>Application written on C++ with use OpenGL and OpenCV for communicate with available drones in the networks. Also will show drone status and control it. *Image downloaded from internet and will be changed for screenshot.
Status: Active Development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to connect DSI and CSI cable to tinker board</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/blog/how-to-connect-dsi-and-csi-cable-to-tinker-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/blog/how-to-connect-dsi-and-csi-cable-to-tinker-board/</guid>
      <description>DSI, CSI cable can be use will no difference, those cable is the same. CSI connect to the middle of tinker board, please refer icon print on board as follows:  DSI connect to the boundary of tinker board, please refer icon print on board as follows:
DSI panel need extra 5V power. You can USB to supply, or thinker board can output 5V by GPIO PIN, red line is for positive(+)，black line is for negative(-) , as follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics Primer for 3D Software Developer (Coordinate Systems)</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/blog/math-primer-coordinate-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 14:51:12 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/blog/math-primer-coordinate-systems/</guid>
      <description>This article assumes you have a minimum understanding vectors, and matrices. I will simply show applications of vectors and matrices and how they apply to game programming.
In this article, I would like to provide a brief math primer for people who would like to get involved in game programming. This is not an exhaustive explanation of all the math theory that one will have to know in order to be a successful game programmer, but it’s the very minimum amount of information that is necessary to know before you can begin as a game programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPU-9250 Accelerometer, Gyroscope and Magnetometer Code</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/blog/mpu-9250-accelerometer-gyroscope-and-magnetometer-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/blog/mpu-9250-accelerometer-gyroscope-and-magnetometer-code/</guid>
      <description>In this Article you will get the code and library for MPU-9250 module. Watch video instruction on how to use MPU-9250.
 Get MPU-9250 Library from Github Data sheet for MPU-9250 MPU-9250 Register Map Get Library from Robojax.com I2C scanner Code and Video Guide to interfacing MPU9250 Gyroscope, Magnetometer and Accelerometer with a Raspberry Pi Arduino Nano: Accelerometer Gyroscope Compass MPU9250 I2C Sensor With Visuino  /* * Library: https://github.com/bolderflight/MPU9250 Basic_I2C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/blog/awesome-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 14:51:12 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/blog/awesome-cpp/</guid>
      <description>Awesome C++
 Standard Libraries Frameworks Artificial Intelligence Asynchronous Event Loop Audio Biology BitTorrent CLI Compression Concurrency Containers Cryptography Database Debug Game Engine GUI Graphics Image Processing Internationalization Inter-process communication JSON Logging Machine Learning Math Memory Allocation Multimedia Networking PDF Physics Regular Expression Robotics Scientific Computing Scripting Serialization Sorting Video Virtual Machines Web Application Framework XML Miscellaneous  Software
 Compiler Online Compiler Debugger Integrated Development Environment Build Systems Static Code Analysis Coding Style Tools  Resources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>to Lviv - Tourist website</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/projects/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 14:51:12 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/projects/4/</guid>
      <description>Information tourism portal of Lviv region - search of tours, reservation of apartments, filter of restaurants by type of cuisine, places of recreation, and business meetups, geolocation.
Web Development geolocation, jquery, javascript, docker, apache-solr, drupal, object-oriented-php, twitter-bootstrap
Status: in progress&amp;hellip;
Link: https://tolviv.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPA - Serial Port Analyzer</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/projects/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 14:51:12 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/projects/5/</guid>
      <description>Cross platform system utility (MacOS X, Linux, Windows) for serial ports monitoring UART RS-232/422/485. The program monitors, displays, logs and analyzes all serial port activity in a system. Perfect software solution for serial port monitoring.
Status: in progress&amp;hellip;
Link: https://github.com/eneus/SPA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awal 10</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/projects/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/projects/7/</guid>
      <description>News WEB site for Arabian world. Customer asked about full redesign and data restructe WEB site based on WordPress CMS.
Status: Done.
Link: http://awal10.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll Docker Container</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/projects/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 14:51:12 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/projects/6/</guid>
      <description>Distribution for FrontEnd developer and generate static websites.
Design is not just what it looks like and feels like. Design is how it works.
Status: Done.
Link: https://github.com/eneus/jekyll</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drupal8 - Unable to determine class for field...</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/blog/drupal8-unable-to-determine-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 12:52:36 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/blog/drupal8-unable-to-determine-field/</guid>
      <description>One possible way is that your module is missing from the codebase or has been improperly uninstalled and you&amp;rsquo;ve still a field which is using that missing module.
Try the following drush commands to remove the broken field:
drush sqlq &amp;quot;DELETE FROM cache_config&amp;quot; drush sqlq &amp;quot;DELETE FROM config WHERE name = &#39;field.storage.xxx.xxx&#39; OR data LIKE &#39;%field.storage.xxx.xxx%&#39;&amp;quot; drush sqlq &amp;quot;DELETE FROM config_snapshot WHERE name = &#39;field.storage.xxx.xxx&#39; OR data LIKE &#39;%field.storage.xxx.xxx%&#39;&amp;quot;  Warning: Don&amp;rsquo;t execute above commands on master/live database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homeless pets</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/projects/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 14:51:12 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/projects/3/</guid>
      <description>Information base of animals Kharkiv Center for the Content of Homeless Animals. Search for lost, registration and adoption of homeless animals. Work with volunteers. Adaptive layout, filters. Integration with social media.
Web Development drupal, object-oriented-php, responsive-design, web-design
Status: Done.
Link: https://animals-city.org/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Back to Top&#39; Button for your website</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/blog/back-to-op-button-to-yourwebsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 12:52:36 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/blog/back-to-op-button-to-yourwebsite/</guid>
      <description>A Back To Top button is something that a lot of you have probably seen on many websites. It’s that arrow that appears at the bottom right or left corner of a web page when you start scrolling it. When clicked, it brings you back to the top of the page.
If you want to add a back to top button while you&amp;rsquo;re still designing a website, or just curious about how you can build one on your own, this article for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Jekyll Docker container</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/blog/how-to-use-jekyll-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 12:52:36 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/blog/how-to-use-jekyll-container/</guid>
      <description>Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s Docker Container with Demo Content and demo site.
Plugins included:
- Jekyll: 3.8.3 -- jekyll-paginate -- jekyll-sitemap -- jekyll-feed -- jekyll-multisite -- jekyll-github-metadata -- jekyll-seo-tag -- jekyll-watch -- jekyll-sass-converter -- jekyll-assets -- jekyll-multiple-languages-plugin - Compass: 1.0.3 - NodeJS: 8.9.3 -- NPM: 5.5.1 -- Yarn: 1.3.2  The first of all: Install Docker:
 On Linux Ubuntu/Debian:  https://docs.docker.com/install/linux/docker-ce/ubuntu/ https://docs.docker.com/install/linux/docker-ce/debian/
 On MacOS:  https://docs.docker.com/docker-for-mac/install/
 On Windows:  https://docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Security Center</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/projects/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 12:52:36 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/projects/1/</guid>
      <description>Business Security Center (BSC) website had needed SEO optimization and a total redesign and data restructure for securing high professional level of services and achievement of maximum efficiency of company activity.
First required for developing was to provide comfort navigation and quick search of services, products and equipment, since the company granting a full range of security and safety services for private individuals or companies as well as sells integrated security solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Events</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/projects/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 14:39:16 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/projects/2/</guid>
      <description>City Events - Started as distribution and implemented like regional WEBsite &amp;lsquo;Моя Жовківщина&amp;rsquo;.
Regional news portal with news, blogs, organizations, events, publications. Registration of users, contests, photo reports. Search engine ApacheSolr. Filter, Geolocation, social integration, SEO optimization. Development based on Docker Containers with flexibility extensions.
Web Development drupal, php, twitter-bootstrap, responsive-design
Status: Done.
Link: https://myzhovkva.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gallery</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/gallery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I am Ivan</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Software Developer expert with over 10 years experience in setup and customization different software solutions and embedded systems like STM32 and Raspberry Pi or analogs based on ARM microprocessors.  Durring study in University, to earn a money worked like a WEB developer, hence I have a big experience in the developing of WEB aplications and cross-platform complex environments for different networks protocols and API&#39;s. Some my own projects or that are not under NDA agreement you can see in the section &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://eneus.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eneus.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>